let's look at the solution to our parity
quiz we are adding parity to our memory
which consists of eight arrays so now
the question is should we add parity to
each row of data and then when we read
out the row into the row buffer we
checked for parity and report an error
or should we have the modules as is and
just add two more that will hold the
parity both approaches have exactly the
same number of extra bits we are adding
but the approach of having extra modules
as opposed to changing the modules is
preferable for two reasons one is that
this way we can design this memory
arrays both for unprotected and for
protected memories the protected
memories will just have additional
arrays but the design of each array is
the same if we decided to add parity
bits here then depending on exactly how
many parity bits we are adding for how
many data bits and weather we are having
parity at all we would need to redesign
our memory array every time the second
reason why using redundancy at a coarser
grain rather than finer grain tends to
work better is because let's say that an
array fails by reading zeros for the
entire row this is not such a
far-fetched error in that case what we
have is if we have the parity bits added
to each row the row still has correct
parity so a single failure for example
in the row decoder will just read the
wrong row it still has the right parity
if however we separate the modules with
the parity then each of the modules will
operate on its own so the error of a row
decoder here will cause this bit now to
be wrong in every 8-bit word we read but
if these other arrays are still working
correctly then we can still detect that
because the parity is somewhere else so
this is kind of similar to doing
geographical distribution of our
computers for redundancy pretty much the
further away the protection bits are the
more likely they will protect us against
large failures in any single component